<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin/>
                <title>Oyster Habitats Florida</title>
                <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                <onlink>http://geodata.myfwc.com/datasets/a78160f5acaf4439b49f9fbef4c100ac_5</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>This GIS data set represents oyster coverage for available study areas in the state of Florida. Not all areas have been mapped, but this dataset represents the oyster data available to FWRI as of November, 2020. Source dates vary and many studies are much older than the compilation date. See the Source Information section for more details.</abstract>
            <purpose>This GIS data set was created to represent oysters for general mapping purposes only. Different studies used different methodologies and not all areas have been mapped.</purpose>
            <supplinf>Data were provided from the following sources: Apalachicola National Estuarine Reserach Reserve, Research Planning, Inc., U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Suwannee River Water Management District, Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, Palm Beach County, Scheda Ecological Associates, Inc and Rookery Bay National Estuarine Research Reserve, Northwest Florida Water Management District, Ibis Environmental, Inc., U.S. Geological Survey, South Florida Water Management District, Volety, A. and Savarese, M., Florida Gulf Coast University, University of New Hampshire and The Nature Conservancy, Loxahatchee River District, University of Central Florida, City of Naples, Florida Department of Agriculture and Consumer Services, Sarasota County, St. Johns River Water Management District, Southwest Florida Water Management District, US Fish and Wildlife Service National Wetlands Inventory, FDEP Indian River Lagoon Aquatic Preserves, Smithsonian Marine Station. More detailed citations are provided in the Source Contribution sections of the metadata. Prior to July 1, 2004, the Fish and Wildlife Research Institute (FWRI) was known as the Florida Marine Research Institute (FMRI). The institute name has not been changed in historical data sets or references to work completed by the Florida Marine Research Institute. The institute name has been changed in references to ongoing research, new research, and contact information.</supplinf>
        </descript>
        <timeperd>
            <timeinfo>
                <rngdates>
                    <begdate>19920101</begdate>
                    <enddate>20200101</enddate>
                </rngdates>
            </timeinfo>
            <current>Ground condition</current>
        </timeperd>
        <status>
            <progress>Complete</progress>
            <update>None planned</update>
        </status>
        <spdom>
            <bounding>
                <westbc>-86.918535</westbc>
                <eastbc>-79.900781</eastbc>
                <northbc>30.405035</northbc>
                <southbc>25.834097</southbc>
            </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
                <themekey>biota</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>FWC Theme</themekt>
                <themekey>mapping</themekey>
                <themekey>coastal</themekey>
                <themekey>benthic</themekey>
                <themekey>GIS</themekey>
            </theme>
            <place>
                <placekt>Florida Counties</placekt>
                <placekey>Pasco</placekey>
                <placekey>Levy</placekey>
                <placekey>Manatee</placekey>
                <placekey>Indian River</placekey>
                <placekey>Pinellas</placekey>
                <placekey>Martin</placekey>
                <placekey>Dixie</placekey>
                <placekey>St. Lucie</placekey>
                <placekey>Palm Beach</placekey>
                <placekey>Brevard</placekey>
                <placekey>Franklin</placekey>
                <placekey>Gulf</placekey>
                <placekey>Taylor</placekey>
                <placekey>Hernando</placekey>
                <placekey>Jefferson</placekey>
                <placekey>Hillsborough</placekey>
                <placekey>Citrus</placekey>
                <placekey>Wakulla</placekey>
            </place>
            <place>
                <placekt>Water Management Districts</placekt>
                <placekey>Southwest Florida</placekey>
                <placekey>St. Johns River</placekey>
                <placekey>Northwest Florida</placekey>
                <placekey>South Florida</placekey>
                <placekey>Suwannee River</placekey>
            </place>
            <place>
                <placekt>FWC Place</placekt>
                <placekey>Florida</placekey>
            </place>
            <place>
                <placekt>FWC Regions</placekt>
                <placekey>Northwest</placekey>
                <placekey>South</placekey>
                <placekey>North Central</placekey>
                <placekey>Northeast</placekey>
                <placekey>Southwest</placekey>
            </place>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>Available without restriction. All data must be verified by Principal Investigator or Group Database Analyst prior to release. It is strongly recommended that this data is directly acquired from FWC and not indirectly through other sources which may have changed the data in some way. FWC makes no claims as to the data's suitability for other purposes.</accconst>
        <useconst>Acknowledgement of the FWC-FWRI (Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute) as the data source would be appreciated in any products developed from these data, and such acknowledgment as is standard for citation and legal practices for data source is expected by users of this data. Please cite the original metadata when using portions of the record to create a similar record of slightly altered data, such as reprojection. If any data are modified or adjusted, please share the edited information with FWC. Users should be aware that comparison with other data sets for the same area from other time periods may be inaccurate due to inconsistencies resulting from changes in mapping conventions, data collection, and computer processes over time. FWC shall not be liable for improper or incorrect use of this data. These data are not legal documents and are not to be used as such. This is not a survey data set and should not be utilized as such. These data are not to be used for navigation.</useconst>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>FWC-FWRI (Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute)</cntorg>
                    <cntper>GISLibrarian</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS Data Librarian</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</address>
                    <address>100 Eighth Avenue Southeast</address>
                    <city>St. Petersburg</city>
                    <state>Florida</state>
                    <postal>33701</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>727-896-8626</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>727-893-1679</cntfax>
                <cntemail>GISLibrarian@MyFWC.com</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <datacred>These data are compiled data from various source organizations listed in the Source Citations.</datacred>
        <secinfo>
            <secsys>FWRI-DC</secsys>
            <sechandl>Available without restriction</sechandl>
        </secinfo>
        <native>ESRI ArcCatalog 9.3.0.1745</native>
    </idinfo>
    <dataqual>
        <attracc>
            <attraccr>Attributes are accurate. All polygons have been reclassified as simply "oyster" - see source data sets for the original classification.</attraccr>
        </attracc>
        <logic>These data are logically consistent. Polygon topology is present and a topology was run with the "must not overlap" rule applied. All overlaps were dissolved.</logic>
        <complete>This data set is not complete for the state of Florida. It only represents oysters in areas where they have been mapped. If you know of another oyster mapping study to add to this compilation, please contact GISLibrarian@myfwc.com.</complete>
        <posacc>
            <horizpa>
                <horizpar>Positional accuracy has not been tested for the compilation. See Source information for the accuracy of the source data sets.</horizpar>
            </horizpa>
        </posacc>
        <lineage>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20170330</pubdate>
                        <title>seagrass_springscoast_2016</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>12000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <mdattim>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>20160101</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>20160120</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>20160301</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                        </mdattim>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>seagrass_springscoast_2016</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Oyster data (FLUCCS 6540) were selected from this dataset. All oyster polygons were included, completely replacing the previous 2007 data in the area. Oyster Bars using code of 6540. Areas 0.25 acre or greater in size this classification includes oyster bars / reefs and oyster shell hash. Both live and dead oyster habitat will be classified under this class if they achieve dominance within the cover type and meet the minimum mapping unit greater than 0.25 acre. Citation: Southwest Florida Water Management District. 2016. Seagrass data for 2016 in Springs Coast Florida. GIS, maps and Survey: Shapefile Library. http://data-swfwmd.opendata.arcgis.com/datasets/efff366cd06e4f6d85b2f3d96b572aff_22, accessed October 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20051202</pubdate>
                        <title>benthic_SRWMD_2001</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <mdattim>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>20011119</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>20011121</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                        </mdattim>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>benthic_SRWMD_2001</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Oyster polygons coded 6540 were selected from this data set. The data were interpreted from 1:24,000 aerial photography. This data set only mapped oyster bars, oyster beds and oyster hash that make up the Waccasassa Reefs and Corrigan Reef. Other oyster bars within seagrass beds or tidal flats were not included. In areas overlapped by oyster polygons from the SRWMD landcover 2010-11, the more recent data were used. Citation: Suwannee River Water Management District. 2001b. Suwannee River Water Management District Seagrass 2001 Seagrass - Northern Big Bend. www.srwmd.state.fl.us/index.aspx?NID=319, accessed June 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20081219</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_loxahatchee_2008</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20080101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_loxahatchee_2008</srccitea>
                <srccontr>This data set is used to supplement the 2011 US Army Corps of Engineers data in the Loxahatchee River - any overlaps were resolved in favor of the more recent 2011 data. Citation: Howard B, Arrington DA. 2008. Loxahatchee river water quality and biological monitoring. Task 2: final report. Assessment of 2007-2008 Loxahatchee river oyster mapping &amp; recruitment. Loxahatchee River District. http://loxahatcheeriver.org/pdf/OY2007-08.pdf, accessed December 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20020927</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_big_bend_poly</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20011101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_big_bend_poly</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Polygons oyster codes 6540 (oysters) and 6541 (oysters patchy) were reclassified as live oysters and 6542 (oysters remnant) was reclassified as dead. In areas overlapped by oyster polygons from the SRWMD landcover 2010-11, the more recent data were used. Citation: Suwannee River Water Management District. 2001. Suwannee River Water Management District Suwannee Estuary 2001 oyster habitat mapping project. www.srwmd.state.fl.us/index.aspx?NID=319, accessed May 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>19860101</pubdate>
                        <title>benthic_apalachbay_poly_H</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>19700101</begdate>
                            <enddate>19850101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>benthic_apalachbay_poly_H</srccitea>
                <srccontr>This data set covers more of Apalachicola Bay than the 2006 USGS dataset. During the OIMMP project, local experts identified this as a historical map that is used to supplement the 2006 data. The COMMENTS field s used to identify polygons from this data set as historical data. Citation: Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission. 1986. Benthic Habitat Apalachicola Bay Florida Historic. Florida Marine Research Institute, St. Petersburg, Florida.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20160601</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_sarasota_2008_2012</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20080101</begdate>
                            <enddate>20120101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_sarasota_2008_2012</srccitea>
                <srccontr>"Reef" polygons were included in the statewide compilation. This data set was used to supplement the 2018 SWFWMD oyster data that were also present in the area. Any overlaps were resolved in favor of the 2018 data. Citation: Meaux KL, Grimes JD, Perry JS, Janneman RA. 2016. Mapping Oyster Habitat in Sarasota County Florida Waters. Sarasota County Water Atlas. http://www.sarasota.wateratlas.usf.edu/upload/documents/SC-Oyster-Mapping-Report_6-2-2016.pdf, accessed December, 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20040101</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_caloosahatchee_2004</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20040101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_caloosahatchee_2004</srccitea>
                <srccontr>All polygons from this dataset were used. Citation: Volety, A. and Savarese, M. 2004. GIS oyster reef mapping in the Caloosahatchee River and Estero Bay. South Florida Water Management District, Technical Report.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20050101</pubdate>
                        <title>seagrass_santarosa_2003</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>12000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20030101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>seagrass_santarosa_2003</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Selected out the MOL category (oysters). Oysters were only mapped where verified by ground-truthing. These data used as-is. Seagrass Pensacola Bay and Santa Rosa Sound Florida 2003 Originator: U.S. Geological Survey, National Wetlands Research Center.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20010503</pubdate>
                        <title>seagrass_esterobay_1999_H</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <mdattim>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>19991226</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>19991209</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                        </mdattim>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>seagrass_esterobay_1999_H</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Oysters were mapped, in addition to seagrass for the study area Pine Island Sound, Matlacha Pass, San Carlos Bay, the lower Caloosahatchee River, and Estero Bay, in 1999. Polygons with oyster code 6540 (oysters) were used from this data set. In areas of overlap with 2004 Caloosahatchee and 2004 Estero, the more recent data were used. Citation: Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission and South Florida Water Management District 1999. Benthic Habitats of Estero Bay Area, Florida 1999 Geoform. https://data.noaa.gov/dataset/benthic-habitats-of-estero-bay-area-florida-1999-geoform, accessed June 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20190315</pubdate>
                        <title>Seagrass in 2018</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>0</srcscale>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srccitea>Seagrass in 2018</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Polygons coded 6540 were extracted from this data set and used to replace previous 2016 mapping data in Tampa Bay and to fill in data gaps. All oyster polygons from this data set were used. Citation: Southwest Florida Water Management District. 2020. Seagrass in 2018. GIS, maps and Survey: Shapefile Library. https://data-swfwmd.opendata.arcgis.com/datasets/seagrass-in-2018, accessed December 2020.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20080101</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_everglades</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <mdattim>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>20080101</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>20040101</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>19990101</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                        </mdattim>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_everglades</srccitea>
                <srccontr>All polygons in this data set are included as oyster polygons. Notes present in the source data regarding quality are included as comments. Citation: Volety AK, Savarese M, Hoye B, Loh AN. 2009a. Landscape pattern: Present and past distribution of oysters in south Florida coastal complex (Whitewater Bay/Oyster Bay/Shark to Robert’s Rivers). Completed by Florida Gulf Coast University for the South Florida Water Management District. Fort Myers, Florida. https://www.researchgate.net/publication/234025368_Landscape_Pattern_Present_and_Past_Distribution_of_Oysters_in_South_Florida_Coastal_Complex_Whitewater_BayOyster_BayShark_to_Robert's_Rivers, accessed April 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20150101</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_intertidal_apalachbay_2012</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20120101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_intertidal_apalachbay_2012</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Univeristy of New Hampshire mapped intertidal oyster reefs using 2012 satellite imagery. All polygons from thisd data set were used. Citation: Grizzle R, Ward K, Geselbracht L, Birch A. 2017. Apalachicola Bay Florida Intertidal Oyster (Crassostrea virginica) Reef Mapping and Characterization. Final Report to the Florida State Wildlife Grants Program</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20120801</pubdate>
                        <title>ESI Florida Panhandle (Invertebrates)</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20120101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>ESI Florida Panhandle (Invertebrates)</srccitea>
                <srccontr>"Eastern Oyster" with a medium or high concentration was reselected from the panhandle ESI invertebrates dataset for Pensacola Bay, Choctawhatchee Bay, and St. Andrew Bay areas. Citation: Research Planning, Inc. 2012. Sensitivity of coastal environments and wildlife to spilled oil. West Florida Atlas. Prepared for the Florida Department of Environmental Protection. Tallahassee, Florida. http://ocean.floridamarine.org/esimaps/pdf/Panhandl/INDEX.pdf, accessed January 2018.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <title>Tampa Bay Oyster Reef Mapping 2020</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srccitea>Tampa Bay Oyster Reef Mapping 2020</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Source: FWRI, Tampa Bay Oyster Reef Mapping 2020. This mapping effort focused on previously unmapped oyster reefs located in Tampa Bay. This effort is intended as a supplement to previous aerial photointerpretation of oyster reefs conducted by the Southwest Florida Water Management District in 2018 (seagrass_swfwmd_2018). Imagery used for photointerpretation of oyster reefs included ESRI base imagery (NASA Blue Marble: Next Generation and icubed Nationwide Prime 1 m resolution imagery) and Google Earth version 7.3.3 satellite and aerial historic imagery. Only live oyster reefs on natural substrate were classified for this effort. Ground truthing is described in the full report, available at: https://ocean.floridamarine.org/OIMMP/Resources/Tampa_Bay_Oyster_Mapping_2020.pdf</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20190101</pubdate>
                        <title>oyster_suwannee_fwri_2019</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20190101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oyster_suwannee_fwri_2019</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Source: FWRI, Suwannee Sound Oyster Reef Mapping 2019. This mapping effort focused on previously unmapped intertidal oyster reefs located in tidal creeks and near-shore waters located to the north and south of the Suwannee River. This effort is intended as a supplement to previous aerial photointerpretation of oyster reefs conducted by AGRA Baymont, Inc. for the Suwannee River Water Management District (SRWMD) in 2001. Imagery used for photointerpretation of oyster reefs included Landsat imagery (USGS/NASA) and Florida Department of Transport mosaics (FDOT 2011-2014). Twelve percent of the reefs identified were visited for groundtruthing and it was determined the accuracy rate was 99%. This mapping effort did not separate between live and dead patches of oyster reef. Full report available: http://ocean.floridamarine.org/OIMMP/Resources/Suwannee River Oyster Mapping 2019.pdf</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <title>benthic_rbnerr_2014</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20140101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>benthic_rbnerr_2014</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Polygons classified as 6540 "Oysters" from this data set were included. This data set replaces the previously mapped partial rbnerr data set. All oyster polygons from this data set were used (minimum mapping unit of 0.25 acres). Citation: Scheda Ecological Associates, Inc and Rookery Bay National Estuarine Research Reserve. 2015. Rookery Bay Watershed Engineering Research Project Task 3.6.3 – Final Report and Map. Tampa, Florida. https://rookerybay.org/images/learn/research-rm/RestoreRB_docs/7-Benthic.habitat.map.Task3.6.3FinalReport.pdf, accessed April 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20100601</pubdate>
                        <title>landuse_nwfwmd_2009_10</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20090101</begdate>
                            <enddate>20100101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>landuse_nwfwmd_2009_10</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Polygons coded 6540 were extracted from this data set and used to replace 1992 oyster mapping within the area of the NWFWMD. All oyster polygons from this data set were used. Previous data from Apalachicola Bay (2006) and Santa Rosa Sound (2003) were retained in the compilation. Citation: Northwest Florida Water Management District 2010. Northwest Florida Water Management District Land Use Land Cover 2009–2010. www.fgdl.org/metadataexplorer/explorer.jsp, accessed June 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <title>Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, FDEP Indian River Lagoon Aquatic Preserves, and Smithsonian Marine Station 2018</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20160101</begdate>
                            <enddate>20180101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, FDEP Indian River Lagoon Aquatic Preserves, and Smithsonian Marine Station 2018</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Indian River Lagoon, reefs are digitized on a periodic, ongoing basis (delineated by Trimble GPS). This dataset does not represent all oyster reefs within the study area. Source: FWC et al. (Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, FDEP Indian River Lagoon Aquatic Preserves, and Smithsonian Marine Station). 2018. Central Indian River Lagoon Mapping Project. In prep.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20170101</pubdate>
                        <title>oyster_westbay_2017</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srccitea>oyster_westbay_2017</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Restored oyster reefs mapped using sidescan sonar. All polygons from this source were used. Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission 2017. Side scan sonar of Oyster Reef Habitat Restoration in St. Andrew Bay, FL http://www.nfwf.org/gulf/Documents/fl-st-andrew-oyster-14.pdf</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20100101</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_panhandle_fdacs</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20100101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_panhandle_fdacs</srccitea>
                <srccontr>These data are from the Gulf States Marine Fisheries report "The Oyster Fishery of The Gulf of Mexico United States: A Regional Management Plan". These polygons are used in the Panhandle estuaries. Note: A set of hand-drawn oyster maps were created by FDACS personnel for the panhandle using NOAA navigation charts and verified in survey and monitoring efforts. These maps were then digitized by FWC to create the FDACS 2009 – 2010 dataset. While a report is not available regarding the methodology for the creation of these maps, these oyster maps were published in Section 17 of the Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission Regional Management Plan (VanderKooy 2012). Citation: VanderKooy S. (ed). 2012. The Oyster Fishery of the Gulf of Mexico, United States: A Regional Management Plan – 2012 Revision. Publication No. 202, Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission, Ocean Springs, Mississippi. http://www.gsmfc.org/publications/GSMFC%20Number%20202.pdf, accessed December 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20110501</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_mosquitolagoon_2009_poly</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20090101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_mosquitolagoon_2009_poly</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Live, Dead, and Restored oyster reef polygons. Citation: Walters L, Garvis S. 2012. Mosquito Lagoon Oyster Habitat Mapping Project Final Report. Project No. CESU H5000070400. Prepared by the University of Central Florida for the National Park Service.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <title>landuse_srwmd_2010_11</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20100101</begdate>
                            <enddate>20110101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>landuse_srwmd_2010_11</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Polygons coded 6540 "Oyster" were added to the compilation. All oyster polygons were included. Citation: Suwannee River Water Management District. 2011. Suwannee River Water Management District Land Use Land Cover 2010–2011. www.srwmd.state.fl.us/index.aspx?NID=319, accessed June 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20160101</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_sjrwmd_2015</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20090101</begdate>
                            <enddate>20160101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_sjrwmd_2015</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Oysters were mapped by the SJRWMD and UCF. All polygons were categorized as "oyster" and existing live/dead attribute information was preserved. All polygons from this source were used. Citation: St. Johns River Water Management District. 2016. Northern coastal basin intercoastal oysters map. www.arcgis.com/home/item.html?id=ac2979f9260e404f874a5f765daeaaa3, accessed April 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20110801</pubdate>
                        <title>benthic_SFestuaries_USACE_2011</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20100101</begdate>
                            <enddate>20110101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>benthic_SFestuaries_USACE_2011</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Data classified as "oyster" were used from this data set. All polygons from this data set in the St. Lucie and Loxahatchee River areas were used in the compilation. In the Caloosahatchee River area, local experts through the OIMMP project identified oyster_caloosahatchee_2004 (Volety and Savarese) as a more representative source. Citation: U.S. Army Corps of Engineers. 2011. Benthic habitat mapping and substrate characterization in the northern estuaries, Florida. Prepared by Dial Cordy and Associates, Inc. http://141.232.10.32/pm/ssr_2014/docs/ne_benthic_substrate_2011.pdf, accessed December 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20040101</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_StLucieEstuary_2003</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20040101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_StLucieEstuary_2003</srccitea>
                <srccontr>This is a polygon file containing data for an oyster survey conducted in fall 2003 in the St. Lucie Estuary, Florida. Oyster bed perimeter was mapped using GPS. No oysters were mapped in channel areas greater than 8 feet deep since initial grid-based surveys did not find evidence of oysters at that depth. LIVE_BED attribute indicated whether a bed was live or not and this was translated into the OYSTER attribute. In areas of overlap with 2011 SFWMD data, the more recent data were used. Citation: Ibis Environmental, Inc. 2004. 2003 St. Lucie Estuary American Oyster mapping study. Prepared for the South Florida Water Management District, West Palm Beach, Florida.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <title>oysters_sebastian_2006_poly</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20051115</begdate>
                            <enddate>20060329</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_sebastian_2006_poly</srccitea>
                <srccontr>This data set includes the location and coverage area of most major oyster reefs within the Sebastian River. Each oyster reef was mapped using Real-Time Kinematic GPS (RTK GPS). Transect surveys were conducted at 1-m intervals across the face of the reef, perpendicular to the long-axis of the reef and extending from border to border. The latitude, longitude and height (elevation) data for each 1-m interval were collected using the RTK GPS rover unit. No data points were taken outside the perimeter of the reef. There were several small polygons that were DISSOLVEd by FWRI to remove overlap. Percent live/dead was recorded in the source data. A polygon is classified as a live bed if any live oysters were found within it. Citation: Gambordella M, McEachron L, Beals C, Arnold WS. 2007. Establishing baselines for monitoring the response of oysters in southeast Florida to changes in freshwater input. Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission, St. Petersburg, FL.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20070101</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_apalachbay_2006_poly</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>30000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <mdattim>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>20070101</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                            <sngdate>
                                <caldate>20060101</caldate>
                            </sngdate>
                        </mdattim>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_apalachbay_2006_poly</srccitea>
                <srccontr>We used all "dredge/oyster" and "oyster" from this data set. The interpretation is based on the sidescan sonar imagery, the bathymetry, available sediment sample information, and seafloor observations. Citation: Twichell DC, Andrews BD, Edmiston HL, Stevenson, WR. 2007. Geophysical mapping of oyster habitats in a shallow estuary; Apalachicola Bay, Florida. U.S. Geological Survey. https://pubs.er.usgs.gov/publication/ofr20061381 , accessed February 2018.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>19920101</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_nw_fl_1992</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>19920101</begdate>
                            <enddate>19930101</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_nw_fl_1992</srccitea>
                <srccontr>This data set gives oyster polygons in the Panhandle and Big Bend areas, interpreted from 1:24,000 natural color aerial photography. It is not an exhaustive mapping effort of oysters, as oysters were only mapped in areas where seagrass was also mapped. There are local areas where more recent mapping efforts have been completed. This data set was used only in areas where no more recent data were available. Citation: U.S. Geological Survey. 1992. Northeastern Gulf of Mexico seagrass mapping project. USGS National Wetlands Research Center.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20060101</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_naples_poly</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20050101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_naples_poly</srccitea>
                <srccontr>"Oyster Reef" and "Low Density Oyster Clumping" were categorized as "Oyster". All polygons from this data source were used. This data set was a compilation of multiple sources by City of Naples Natural Resources Department. In ares where two of the sources provided were overlapping, the more recent source was used. Additional oyster polygons digitized by City of Naples Natural Resources Department were also included. Citation: City of Naples. 2005. Oyster Reefs GIS data. http://g.naplesgov.com/cityofnaplesgis/data.html, accessed June 2009.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20080429</pubdate>
                        <title>benthic_palmbeach_inshr_2007</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20070101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>benthic_palmbeach_inshr_2007</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Polygons with FLUCCS code 6540 (oyster bars/reef) were selected and classified as "oyster". These data were ERASEd with the extent of the 2011 USACE data, so that in areas of overlap, the more recent data were used. Citation: Palm Beach County. 2008. Final project report for the Palm Beach County 2007 habitat mapping project. Prepared by Avineon Inc. www.oyster-restoration.org/wp-content/uploads/2012/06/2007_PBC_Estuarine_Habitat_Mapping_FinalReport.pdf, accessed June 2015.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20180101</pubdate>
                        <title>Apalachicola NERR, CM Snyder</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20180101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Apalachicola NERR, CM Snyder</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Caitlin Snyder digitized historic "half Moon Plant" in East Bay (Apalachicola). This single polygon is the most representative of the current state of this feature.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20040101</pubdate>
                        <title>oysters_estero_2004</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20040101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>oysters_estero_2004</srccitea>
                <srccontr>All polygons from this data source were used. Citation: Volety, A. and Savarese, M. 2004. GIS oyster reef mapping in the Caloosahatchee River and Estero Bay. South Florida Water Management District, Technical Report.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <pubdate>20170601</pubdate>
                        <title>wetland_fl_nwi_poly</title>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>None</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>19990101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>wetland_fl_nwi_poly</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Oyster data from the National Wetlands Inventory dataset were used in SW Florida where no more recent data were available. NWI (National Wetlands Inventory). 1999. NWI surface waters and wetlands mapper. https://www.fws.gov/wetlands/data/Mapper.html, accessed June 2017.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oyster polygons were selected from the source data sets. Each file was given new attributes to classify based on its source data set and the date of the source data, as well as a generic DESCRIPT attribute to indicate that each polygon represents "Oyster". In areas where source files overlapped, the newest data was used. The "oysters_apalachbay_2006", "benthic_srwmd_2001", and "oysters_big_bend" data sets overlapped the "oysters_nw_fl_1992" data set so their extent was ERASEd from the 1992 dataset. Extent footprints for "benthic_srwmd_2001" and "oysters_big_bend" were estimated based on the description of the study area given by Suwannee River Water Management District since these files only represented oysters, not the full bounding box of the project. Along the northern and southern edges of the study areas, polygons from the "oysters_nw_fl_1992" were preserved if it was unclear whether or not the area had been included in the SRWMD studies. The following data sets contained some small overlaps within the source files: "oysters_tampabay", "oysters_Loxahatchee_Rv_2004", and "oysters_sebastian_2006_poly". These overlaps were eliminated by a DISSOLVE of the full data set. The data set was loaded into ArcSDE.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20080701</procdate>
                <proccont>
                    <cntinfo>
                        <cntperp>
                            <cntper>GISLibrarian</cntper>
                        </cntperp>
                        <cntpos>GISLibrarian</cntpos>
                        <cntaddr>
                            <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                            <address>Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</address>
                            <address>100 Eighth Avenue Southeast</address>
                            <city>St. Petersburg</city>
                            <state>Florida</state>
                            <postal>33701</postal>
                        </cntaddr>
                        <cntvoice>727-896-8626</cntvoice>
                        <cntfax>727-893-1679</cntfax>
                        <cntemail>GISLibrarian@MyFWC.com</cntemail>
                    </cntinfo>
                </proccont>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oysters for Estero Bay area were added to the compilation.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20080901</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oysters from 2003 Pensacola Bay and Santa Rosa Sound, and 2007 SJRWMD were added to the compilation.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20090330</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oysters for Springs Coast were added to the compilation</procdesc>
                <procdate>20090601</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oysters from the Rookery Bay dataset were added to the compilation. Additional polygons are present in the source data, labeled "Sparse SAV or Oyster". These were not included in the compilation.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20100401</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oysters from the Mosquito Lagoon 2009 data set were added to the compilation. An additional attribute 'OYSTER' was added to indicate whether a bed is live, dead, or restored. This fields is only populated if the information is present in the source data.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20111114</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oysters from Palm Beach County 2007, Naples 2006, and USACE 2011 were added to the compilation.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20150401</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Features from the oysters_nw_fl_1992 source in the vicinity of Cedar Key were rectified spatially due to noticable locational errors between the digital data and the real world locations. Only areas where no more recent data exist are included from the oysters_nw_fl_1992 source.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20170101</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Features were added from the oyster_sjrwmd_2015 dataset. All features from this source were used. 3 small overlaps present in the source data were corrected.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20170221</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oyster data from the 2016 SWFWMD seagrass mapping and the 2009-10 NWFWMD land use land cover dataset were added.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20170501</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oyster data from SRWMD 2010-11 landuse, the Everglades, and Rookery Bay NERR (2014) were added.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20170613</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oyster data from NWFWMD 2006-2007 landuse were added in the St. Andrew Bay area.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20170728</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oyster data for 2016 in the Springs Coast area were added. This completely replaces the previous 2007 mapping in the Springs Coast area.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20171010</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>After consultation with local experts through the OIMMP project, USACE 2011 data in the Caloosahatchee River area were removed and replaced with data from Volety and Savarese (2004). The 1999 Estero Bay data were also updated with the 2004 Volety and Savarese data in areas of overlap. Loxahatchee River (2008) oyster mapping was added, completely replacing the 2004 Loxahatchee data.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20180117</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oyster data added from ESI panhandle (2012), with the exception of "LOW" concentration areas. Data added from 2010 FDACS. Oyster "Reef" data added from Sarasota County (2008-2012). Intertidal Apalachicola oysters added (University of New Hampshire, 2012). Historical Apalachicola oysters added (FWRI 1980's). "Half Moon Plant" added (ANERR, 2018). Topology was run and overlap errors were corrected.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20180511</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oyster polygons from "landuse_nwfwmd_2006_07" were removed from St. Andrew Bay, as these areas were later identified as sand. Restored oyster polygons in West Bay (St. Andrew Bay) were added.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20180701</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>In SW Florida oyster from National Wetlands Inventory were added to the compilation. In this area, the wetland data were created from 1999 source imagery.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20181121</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oyster polygons from the Indian River Lagoon (2018) were added.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20190122</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>The 2019 FWRI Suwannee oyster dataset was added to the statewide dataset.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20191106</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Oyster data for 2018 from the Southwest Florida Water Management District were added. 2020 data for Tampa Bay from the FWC's Fish and Wildlife Research Institute was also added. These datasets completely replace the previous 2016 mapping in the Tampa Bay area and fill in data gaps. Where these data overlapped with the prevous 2008-2012 data for Sarasota, the newest data was retained.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20201211</procdate>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
    </dataqual>
    <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
    </spdoinfo>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>oyster_fl_poly</enttypl>
                <enttypd>This data set represents mapped oysters in Florida.</enttypd>
                <enttypds>Producer defined.</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>COMMENTS</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Additional comments from source dataset.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>FWRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Additional comments from source dataset.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>DESCRIPT</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Description of polygon features.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Producer defined.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>"Oyster"</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SOURCEDATE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Date of source.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Producer defined.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Date of source.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>METADATA</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Source metadata title.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Producer defined.</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Metadata title.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OYSTER</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Indicates whether a reef contains live, dead, or restored oysters. This field is only populated if this information was present in the source data.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>FWRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <edom>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomv>Live</edomv>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvd>Live oysters</edomvd>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvds>FWRI</edomvds>
                                                					
                    
                    </edom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <edom>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomv>Dead</edomv>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvd>Dead, remnant oyster reef</edomvd>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvds>FWRI</edomvds>
                                                					
                    
                    </edom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <edom>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomv>Restored</edomv>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvd>Restored oyster reef</edomvd>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvds>FWRI</edomvds>
                                                					
                    
                    </edom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape_Length</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of feature in internal units.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>Shape_area</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Area of feature in internal units squared.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>Esri</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
    </eainfo>
    <distinfo>
        <distrib>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>FWC-FWRI (Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute)</cntorg>
                    <cntper>GISLibrarian</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS Data Librarian</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>100 Eighth Avenue Southeast</address>
                    <address>Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</address>
                    <city>St. Petersburg</city>
                    <state>Florida</state>
                    <postal>33701</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>727-896-8626</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>727-893-1679</cntfax>
                <cntemail>GISLibrarian@MyFWC.com</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <distliab>This data set is in the public domain, and the recipient may not assert any proprietary rights thereto nor represent it to anyone as other than a FWC-FWRI produced data set; it is provided "as-is" without warranty of any kind, including, but not limited to, the implied warranties of merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose. The user assumes all responsibility for the accuracy and suitability of this data set for a specific application. In no event will the staff of the Fish and Wildlife Research Institute be liable for any damages, including lost profits, lost savings, or other incidental or consequential damages arising from the use of or the inability to use this data set.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo>
                    <formname>SHP</formname>
                    <transize>0.033</transize>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                    <onlinopt>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
                                <networkr>http://research.myfwc.com/</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                    </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
            </digform>
            <fees>None. However, persons or organizations requesting information must provide transfer media if FTP is not available and must pay express shipping costs if express shipping is required.</fees>
            <ordering>Contact GIS Librarian by e-mail, telephone, or letter explaining which products are needed and providing a brief description of how the products will be used. Also, provide name and address of the person or organization requesting the products.</ordering>
            <turnarnd>Usually within 10 business days, although, complex requests may take longer</turnarnd>
        </stdorder>
    </distinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20201214</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>FWC-FWRI (Florida Fish and Wildlife Conservation Commission-Fish and Wildlife Research Institute)</cntorg>
                    <cntper>GISLibrarian</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS Data Librarian</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>Fish and Wildlife Research Institute</address>
                    <address>100 Eighth Avenue Southeast</address>
                    <city>St. Petersburg</city>
                    <state>Florida</state>
                    <postal>33701</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>727-896-8626</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>727-893-1679</cntfax>
                <cntemail>GISLibrarian@MyFWC.com</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
        <metac>No restrictions on metadata</metac>
        <metuc>Metadata must be distributed with the data set.</metuc>
        <metsi>
            <metscs>FWRI-MC</metscs>
            <metshd>Metadata must be distributed with the data set.</metshd>
        </metsi>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
